# **Garima Chauhan**

<u>chauhangarima.786@gmail.com</u> | +1-7086547858| Chicago, IL LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/garima-chauhan-83b27860/

Github: <a href="https://github.com/GarimaChauhan16/">https://github.com/GarimaChauhan16/</a> | Bio: <a href="https://garimachauhan16.github.io/">https://garimachauhan16.github.io/</a>

A mechanical engineering postgraduate from Indian Institute of Technology, Delhi, India having worked for 6 years as Computer Aided Analyst in various automobile Industries across India on individual as well as team projects. Recently graduated from **Data Science bootcamp program** from **Northwestern University Chicago** with technical abilities in advanced **Python programming and web scraping**. Maintains an insatiable curiosity to acquire new skills and tackle challenging tasks.

#### **Technical Skills**

Languages: VBA, Python, R, SQL

Data Manipulation & Visualization: Pandas, Matplotlib, Tableau, HTML/CSS/JavaScript, D3,

Plotly, Leaflet

Machine Learning: scikit learn, tensorflow Database: mySQL, postgeSQL, mongoDB

Other: Git, Flask

### **Projects**

#### Pyber | https://github.com/GarimaChauhan16/Pyber

- This project deals with the data of a hypothetical ride sharing company called "Pyber".
- The data contains information about every active driver and historic ride, including details like city, driver count, individual fares, and city type.
- Matplotlib was used to represent the data by building bubble plots and pie charts to showcase the relationships between the key-variables.

#### Weather Changes | https://github.com/GarimaChauhan16/WeatherPy

- Analyzed changes in weather with respect to distance from the equator.
- Pulled data from OpenWeatherMap API to assemble a dataset on over 500 cities.
- Summary statistics and visualizations created using Python, Pandas, and Matplotlib.

## Chicago Housing Prices | https://github.com/GarimaChauhan16/Chicago-Housing-Prices

- Explored the factors influencing housing prices in Chicago. The factors such as number of ammonites, crime rates, poverty, income, short term rentals like Airbnb etc.
- Pulled data from various sources like Kaggle, Zillow, US census website, Yelp.
- Plotted each factor against the median rental values to find out the correlation.
- Performed a multi linear regression analysis to find out how well the housing prices can be explained by each factor by calculating R-square value.

#### Belly Button Biodiversity: https://github.com/GarimaChauhan16/Plotly--

Belly Button Biodiversity

https://belly-button-biodiversity-g.herokuapp.com/

- Built a Full-Stack application to build an interactive dashboard exploring the Belly Button Biodiversity Dataset using Plotly.is, Flask and Heroku.
- Using plotly built pie chart and bubble plot to showcase the sample values and labels.
- Built a gauge chart to plot a weekly washing frequency obtained from the samples.

Using python flask deployed the app into Heroku.

# CTA Ridership Visualization: <a href="https://github.com/GarimaChauhan16/CTA-Ridership-Visualization">https://github.com/GarimaChauhan16/CTA-Ridership-Visualization</a>

- Built a web dashboard which shows a ridership trend for the Chicago Transit Authority (CTA) over the last ten years.
- The data was collected from Chicago Data Portal Website. https://data.cityofchicago.org/
- Used SQL database in Postgres to store the data and created a flask server to load the data into Python.
- Used html, D3, Javascript, Plotly and Leaflet to build final visualization dashboard.

#### Experience

## Mercedes Benz Research & Development, India

2017-2019

Senior CAE Analyst

- Design Validation, Failure simulation, Test Data correlation, Life cycle calculation for the transmission components of Mercedes Benz and AMG cars.
- Created and reviewed Analysis reports for the Computer Aided Simulation tasks and suggested design improvements.
- Created Design guidelines and Standard operating procedure documentation.
- Cross department collaboration with design, material, testing teams to resolve open field issues.

## **Escorts Agri. Machinery, India**

2014-2017

Manager- Engineering Services

- Design Validation, Failure simulation, Life cycle calculation for the tractor components.
- Collaborated with the testing team for the design validation and test correlation.
- Trained and mentored new hires with processes and tools.

#### Mahindra & Mahindra Ltd., India

2012-2014

Deputy Manager- Tractor CAE

- Design Validation, Failure simulation, Life cycle calculation for the tractor components.
- Created load case documents for the test load conditions.
- Created design calculators for optimum component designs based on machine design process using Excel Solver Option.

#### Education

#### Northwestern University, Chicago, Illinois

Data Science Bootcamp

A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in Excel, VBA, Python, R, JavaScript, SQL Databases, Tableau, Big Data, and Machine Learning.

#### Indian Institute of Technology, Delhi, India

Master of Technology

Design Engineering: Department of Applied Mechanics

#### College of Technology, Pantnagar, India

Bachelor of Technology Mechanical Engineering